Beware of the Blob It creeps and leaps
And glides and slides across the floor
Right through the door and all around the wall
A splotch , a blotch Be careful of the Blob
Beware of the Blob It creeps and leaps
And glides and slides across the floor
Right through the door and all around the wall
A splotch , a blotch Be careful of the Blob
Beware of the Blob It creeps and leaps
And glides and slides across the floor
Right through the door and all around the wall
A splotch , a blotch Be careful of the Blob
No .
Well , it 's a shooting star .
I thought you were supposed to wish on shooting stars .
- But I did . - We only saw one .
- But you see a lot of ' em up here at night . - What ?
Well , I mean , there 'sa lot of ' em out at night .
You don 't see ' em in town . That 's why I come up here .
Oh , no , that 's not what I mean .
- I mean , you can see ' em better up here ... - I know what you mean , Steve .
No , no , it 's not what you think , Janey girl .
My name is Jane . Just Jane .
For a little while , I thought that " shooting star " business wasn 't just part of your line .
But it 's not , Janey gir ...
Jane , I 've never brought anyone up here before .
Never ?
Never .
Well , I may be crazy , but ... I believe you .
Well , you 're not crazy .
Boy , that was close !
Come on . I want to see if I can find it .
Shut up . Get back inside .
Get back in there .
Huh . Huh .
I could 've sworn it landed just over this hill .
Maybe it 's like lightning . Sometimes you think it 's striking right next door ,
and it 's really miles away .
No , I still think it 's close by .
Well , do you want to go back and try the other road ?
No . Um ... um ...
well , I 'm sorry about the bumpy ride .
It 's all right , Steve .
Well , listen , why don 't we go back to town and I 'll apologize .
I 'll apologize over a sandwich . I mean , on me .
- Okay ? - Okay .
Steve , watch out !
- What was that ? - It looked like an old man .
Where 'd he go ? Hey , you okay ?
Oh ! Take me to a doctor !
- What 's the matter ? - I can 't get it off !
- Well , here , let me try . Maybe I can get it off . - No ! You can 't !
Okay . Come on . We 'll get you in the car .
- Yeah , okay , get in . - It hurts .
Take it easy , now .
Here , better put this on . Take it easy .
We 'll get you there as fast as we can . Boy , I hope the doctor 's in .
Mrs. Porter , Dr. Hallen . I 'm leaving now .
Yes , I 'll be back tomorrow night , probably late .
No , I haven 't forgotten anything .
Ye-Yes , I 'll be fine .
Look , Mrs. Porter , if you 'll just keep your eye on the house while I 'm gone .
Thank you . Good-bye .
Come on !
- Hey , who 's the cowboy ? - That 's no cowboy . That 's Steve Andrews .
- What ? - Yeah , that 's his container . It 's a real dog .
Well , he can 't do that to us .
Hey , Doc . It 's all right . Come on .
Watch his hand .
Hey , Doc Hallen , this man 's been hurt .
Well , come on in .
Wanna get the door ?
In there .
What 's the matter with him ?
I ... I don 't know . He got something on his hand .
- What do you mean ? - Well , we ran into him down on the Old North Road .
- Ran into him ? - No , Doc , we picked him up out on the road .
He was screaming about this thing on his hand .
Let 's take a look . Take it easy , old-timer .
- What is it he 's got on his hand ? - I don 't know , Doc .
It was kind of like ... well , a big blister on his fingers , you know ?
Easy , now . Easy .
How are we gonna help you if you don 't let us see it ?
Doc ! It 's gotten bigger . It was just on his hand before .
Cover him with this , please . I 've got to give him something .
Take it easy , old-timer . Everything 's gonna be all right .
- Steve , uh , you know who he is ? - Huh ?
- Do you have any idea who he is ? - Oh , no , no .
All right , take it easy .
There we are .
- Steve . - Huh ?
Could you drive out to the place you found him ?
See if you can find somebody that knows what happened .
Right . Right .
- Steve ? - Yeah ?
Would you turn out the outside light when you go ?
- I don 't want to be disturbed . - Sure , Doc . Sure .
What 's up ?
- Congratulations . - Yeah ? For what ?
- " For what ? " he says . - Modest .
Mooch , quick , the crown .
Okay , I give up .
You just beat out the champion , pal .
A little while ago when you came into town .
Oh .
I get it . Well , thanks anyway , but you can keep the crown .
No , no , no . Wait a minute , Steve .
You just can 't stop being the champion like that . You 've gotta meet a challenger .
- You mean you ? - Me ?
Did I say anything about a race , guys ?
Huh ? Not a word .
All right , look , it 's been a ball , you know ? But I gotta go .
Yeah ... we know how you go .
We 're just not so sure you should drive around so fast .
Now look , I just don 't have time to prove anything tonight . Do you understand ?
Well , who 's asking you to prove anything ?
We can beat this kiddie car of yours going backwards .
Oh , that 's a foregone transfusion .
Okay .
Now you 're talkin ' , king .
And we 'll do it just like you said .
- What did I say ? - Backwards .
Huh ?
See if you could beat this kiddie car going backwards .
- To the light . - Okay . You say when .
Okay .
When !
I told you . I got to leave now .
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh !
Steve .
All right , what 's this all about ?
Hi , Dave . Hey , what 's up , huh ?
I seem to be missing something . What 's going on ?
We 're just sitting here waiting for the light .
Oh , you mean that light down there .
Yeah .
And you do know you 're on the wrong side of the road ?
I don 't ...
Would you think it was funny if your father ...
if Jane 's father heard you were booked for reckless driving ?
Okay , don 't bring the fathers into this . I 'll never do it again .
- Do what again ? - Huh ?
Do what again ?
What-Whatever you think I 'm doing , Dave .
Like driving on the wrong side of the road ?
Well ... yeah , yeah .
Or maybe even driving backwards ?
Hey , Dave , that 's an idea .
You know that 80 or 90 percent of the accidents are front-end jobs .
You know , in Australia they got airplanes ...
with the seats set in backwards ...
so in case you get a collision , they got ...
no concu ...
No good , huh ?
Okay ... lock me up .
You mean , you were dri ...
Why ?
What am I gonna do with you kids ? You know I don 't wanna haul you in .
No more foolin ' around , Dave . No , I mean it .
I ... swe ... I promise . Right , Jane ? Huh ?
- Right . - See ?
- No more horseplay . - No more horseplay , Dave .
- No , no more fooling around . - Get outta here .
Here they come .
Hey , what happened ?
- Sergeant Bert ? - No , no , no . Dave .
- Oh , you 're lucky it wasn 't Bertsie . - Yeah , you 're not kidding .
- You don 't know the half of it . - What ?
- Last night we seen Gig 's car parked in front of Nancy 's . - Listen to this .
So we decided we 'd move it , hide it on him .
So we 're moving it down the center of the street ...
When along comes Sgt. Bert .
So Mooch tells him we can 't get it started , you know ?
He says , " I don 't care . You 're blocking traffic . Move it out of the way . "
So then he gets out of the car , comes over to us ...
and he 's helping us move Gig 's car .
Just then , Gig comes out of the house ...
and he 's yelling , " Who 's stealing my car ? "
- I thought Bertie would drop his teeth . - I bet he did .
If Gig didn 't cover for us , we would 've been in trouble .
Yeah , you know , I 'd sure hate to cross Bertie again tonight .
Hey , what happened with you and Dave ?
I got a lecture . Promised to be a good boy .
You know , Dave 's a good guy . I think we have been steaming him up a little too much .
There 's about two inches of rubber on the street outside Doc 's house .
Hey , I almost forgot . I gotta do something for the doc .
- What ? - I gotta go up and check on some people .
- You wanna come with me ? - Oh , no , man . We 're going to the flicks .
- At this time of night ? - Yeah , it 's a midnight spook bit .
We got some rumors there 'd be some unprotected women in the balcony .
Well , listen , why don 't you ... Come on , come with us .
You can go to the movies after . It 'll only take a half hour .
- Come on ! - It 's okay with me .
- All right , man , lead the way . - Okay .
Groverton 4771 .
5296 .
Hello . Is Dr. Gilpen there ?
Dr. Hallen .
Oh , he has ?
No , no message . Thanks . Good-bye .
Hello ?
Kate ? Dr. Hallen . I 'm still at the office .
Something 's come up . I 'll need your help right away . No , you 've got to come back .
There 's a man here with some sort of a parasite on his arm .
It 's assimilating his flesh at a frightening speed .
I may have to get ahead of it and amputate .
No , I ... I don 't know what it is or where it came from .
Man , look at that , will you ?
- What is it ? - Wow , I don 't know .
Tony , look .
- Hey , what landed here ? - We must be getting close to the front line .
Hey , why would anybody leave a lantern here ?
- I don 't know . - What is it , Steve ?
- It 's hot . - Watch it .
- A shooting star ? - Hey , we saw that too !
A real big one , like a skyrocket .
- Oh , yeah , about an hour ago . - You think this is it ?
- I don 't know . - Let me see .
Wow , a real piece of sky . Here , Mooch .
You mean that this little pebble has been out there hot-roddin ' around the universe ?
Probably big as the moon when it started .
No kiddin ' ! Let me see it , Mooch .
And this is all that 's left ?
Well , it 's all that 's here .
I 'll bet there is a house close by .
Doesn 't sound like a house . It sounds like a dog .
- Come on , Steve . Let 's go look . - Yeah , sure .
Hey , wait a minute .
Hey , there 's a house .
- Hey , real nice . - You think anybody 's here ?
Hello ? Hello ? Doesn 't look like there 's anybody here at all .
Hey , I can 't see anything but just that little dog .
Oh , Steve , open the door and let him out .
Okay . Come on .
- Come on . Come on . - Come on . Come on .
- Come on , pal . - Come on . Ohhh . Come on out .
- Doesn 't look like anybody was there at all . - Come on .
I guess it 's the old man 's dog .
Don 't you worry , baby . You 'll be all right .
- Think this is the place ? - It sure looks like it .
This is a cozy spot . No neighbors , no cars , no roads , no lights .
Yeah , and no movies . Come on , you guys , let 's get outta here .
Let 's go , Mooch .
I guess there 's nothing else you can find out here , Steve .
No , no , I guess not .
Why don 't you come with us to the spooky show , huh ? You 'd like it .
- No , no thanks . - Ah , you gotta stop takin ' everything so serious-like .
Gotta live a little . You gotta go , you know ?
Yeah , Steve , you gotta hang loose , like me .
- Okay , sure , the spook show . - Come on .
- Let 's go , you guys ! - Yeah , comin ' .
- Steve ? - Yeah .
- What about the dog ? - I don 't know .
I mean , we can 't just leave him here . He 'd starve to death .
- Yeah , that 's right . - Couldn 't we take him with us ?
Sure . I guess that 's the least we could do for the old man . Come on , let 's go .
Oh , hello , Kate . Thanks for coming back .
It 's okay . What do you want me to do ?
You better take his pulse . But don 't touch that material on his right hand .
It absorbs flesh on contact , like an acid .
Doctor , where is he ?
What do you mean ?
Kate , stand still . Don 't move .
It must have absorbed the old man completely .
I don 't know what this is , but it 's got to be killed before it gets any bigger .
- Oh , Doctor , I 'm afraid . - Try to stay as far away from it as you can .
Kate , be calm ! Now do as I say .
Behind you . The trichloroacetic acid .
- Throw it ! - Throw it ?
Yes , but for heaven 's sake , don 't get any of it on your hands .
Doctor , nothing will stop it .
A gun . In my den . I 've got to go for it , Kate .
Now try to stay absolutely still .
- Don 't go . Don 't leave me . - I 'll be right back .
Doctor , come back ! Come back !
Kate , what 's the matter ?
Kate ! Kate , what is it ? Kate !
Kate !
Listen , you stay there , and I 'll go in and tell the doc .
- It doesn 't look like there 's anybody here . - Yeah .
Well , maybe he took the old man to the hospital . Anyway , I 'll check .
Okay .
Listen , I 'm gonna check in the garage and see if the doc 's car is there .
Oh , okay .
Steve . Steve , what 's the matter ?
Steve , tell me what happened .
- I can 't . - Well , what happened ?
- It was so ... - Steve , what is it ?
- It 's got the doc . It 's got ... - What 's the matter with him ?
Just like the thing on the old man 's hand , only it was bigger .
Then it was on his whole head , and then in just a second he disappeared .
- He disappeared ? - He was all gone . He was all gone .
- You know , he just disappeared . - Steve , what are you talking about ?
I 'm sorry . Get in the car , Jane .
Well , what are you gonna do , Steve ?
We 're gonna go to the police . They 'll know what to do .
Well , we can get someone over there tomorrow . Yeah .
- We 'll have someone over there first thing in the morning . - Well , what 's this ?
Hey , watch it , Dave . Don 't mix up the pieces .
Ritchie , you old buzzard . I didn 't know you were a chess player .
It 's like I 've been telling you , Dave . You 're not the only thinker around here .
It 's nothing . Just a hobby , you know ?
Well , wait . Wait a minute . I think this is interesting . Who do you play with ?
Well , late at night when I 'm here by myself and things are pretty slow , I ...
Well , you gotta do something .
You oughta take up chess . Loosen up your gray matter a little .
I guess I 'd better . You 'll have to teach me , Ritchie .
Sure , Dave . Anytime .
Dave , Doc Hallen 's been killed .
- Doc Hallen ? What happened ? - You gotta come now !
Wait a minute , Steve . Tell us what happened .
I 'm trying to tell you . Now this thing , it killed the doc .
What was it ? Out with it , kid .
Well , it 's kind of like a ma ...
It 's kind of like a mass that keeps getting bigger and bigger .
- Come on , Steve , make sense . - I know , I know .
Look , Dave , you gotta see this thing to believe what I 'm telling you .
Maybe the thing you saw was a ... monster ?
Yeah , maybe it was . I don 't know .
Hold on , Jim . Now , what is it , Steve ?
A little while ago it was driving backwards , and now it 's monsters .
Look , he 's not making it up , Dave . Honest .
Dave , I 'm not kidding . Come on over to the doc 's . You can see it for yourself .
You 're crazy if you go . Can 't you see it 's a gag ?
He says Doc Hallen 's dead , Jim . We 've got to check it out .
Let 's go . Ritchie , you mind the store .
Dave , listen ...
East Cornwall , Downingtown H.Q.
Downingtown , East Cornwall H.Q.
Q to K-2 .
Do I read you right ? Q to K-2 ?
Roger .
K-9 to KB-5 .
Shucks .
" This office will be closed all day Saturday . Dr. Hallen . "
- Wait a minute . - What 's the matter ?
The thing might be in there waiting for you .
- Well , we 'll have to take that chance , won 't we ? - I 'm not kidding .
Dr. Hallen ?
Hmm . Seems to be a short circuit in here .
You got your light ?
Everything looks okay .
There . I think this is the room I saw him in .
- It 's locked . - I 'll see if I can find a key that 'll work .
No , the key 's already here . It 's been locked from the inside .
Hello ? Who 's in there ?
Better go around and see if the window 's unlocked .
If it isn 't , break the glass , come in and unlock the door .
- All right . - You 're not gonna let him do that .
Now , don 't worry , Steve . Sergeant Bert knows how to handle himself .
And this is the only way to get to the bottom of this .
- I 'll see if I can find the fuse box . - Okay .
Steve , I wonder where the little dog is .
Yeah .
What do you think happened to him ?
I don 't know .
Well , that 's more like it .
This must have been what blew the fuse .
Jim ?
Wait till you get a load of this mess !
Ohh .
What about this , Steve ?
I don 't know , Dave . But I know I saw the doc .
All right , kid , cut the act . What really happened here ?
- I don 't know . - All of a sudden , your mind is a blank ?
- No . - Steve , are you sure this is the room ?
Yes , I 'm sure of it .
This has been fired .
But I haven 't seen any shot marks around anyplace .
Let me tell you what happened , kid .
You and whoever else was in on this thought you 'd put one over on the police .
- So you break in here , you mess the place up ... - Wait a minute , Jim .
The kids couldn 't have done this . You saw for yourself .
The window was locked from the inside , and so was the door .
They rigged it with string . It 's part of their plan to make us look silly .
I think you 're doing that pretty well by yourself , Sergeant .
Steve , was there anybody else with you ?
No .
How about when I stopped you over on Morgan Street ?
Those kids had nothing to do with this .
- Who were they ? - Why , it was Tony and Mooch .
Those kids ? Well , there 's your answer right there !
They 're just the kind of kids to pull a trick like this .
- But this time they 've gone too far . - What goes on out here ?
- Land 's sakes ! - What are you doing here , Mrs. Porter ?
Boy oh boy oh boy ! Wait till Doctor gets back and sees this !
- Back from where ? - Lieutenant , was it burglars ?
We don 't know yet . Where is Dr. Hallen ?
Johnsonville . A medical convention .
You know , I told him this would happen one of these days ,
the way he leaves everything unlocked .
Of course , it was my fault too . He asked me to keep an eye on the place .
But that 's not true , Dave . He never left .
I don 't think I 've had the pleasure .
This is Steve Andrews , Mrs. Porter .
He seems to think the doctor got into some trouble here tonight .
No , sir ! The doctor don 't know anything about this .
He called me just before he left .
He didn 't leave . Look , Dave , I 'll bet his car is still in the garage .
Might be . Doctor sometimes goes in somebody else 's car .
Dr. Gilpen from over in Groverton .
- Jim , call Dr. Gilpen . - Right .
- He won 't be home . - Just checking .
Mrs. Porter , did you hear any gunshots tonight ?
I sure did ! Tonight and every other night .
The people downstairs have those old movies on their television .
There 's always some shooting or screaming .
Whoever this thief was , he didn 't have to tear up the place like this .
I feel terrible .
Wait a minute , Mrs. Porter . I don 't want this touched .
Well , I don 't want the doctor to come back tomorrow and find the place like this .
- It 's bad enough the window 's broke and all . - But , Mrs. Porter ...
Now , you boys have your work to do , and I have mine .
There 's a criminal walking around out there free as a bird .
You go get him . Let me clean up here .
Mrs. Porter , you don 't understand .
We may want to check here for fingerprints later .
Dr. Gilpen 's on his way to Johnsonville .
Did he pick up Dr. Hallen ?
I spoke with Mrs. Gilpen , and she said that Dr. Hallen had called around 11 : 00 ,
just after her husband left , but she thought they were going together .
- Where can we reach them in Johnsonville ? - I didn 't ask her that .
St. John 's Hotel . That 's where the doctor usually stays .
Well , they should be there in a couple of hours .
We 'll leave word to have him call us when he checks in .
Can 't I just dust around the fingerprints ?
Tomorrow . Well , let 's go , kids .
Dave , this is all wrong .
All right , kid , the show 's over . It was a cute act , but this time it didn 't work .
This locked door business really hung you .
If everything happened like you said , where 's the doctor ?
And where is this old man ? And where is the big , bad monster ?
I don 't know .
Hand me that small hammer , will ya ?
- Why don 't you finish that tomorrow ? - I ain 't gonna be here .
I 'm goin ' on a huntin ' trip .
I didn 't know you was a hunter .
Neither did I.
We got a little cabin up in the south woods , the boys and me .
And I 'm tellin ' you , Marty boy , we 're goin ' up there this weekend ,
and I 'm gonna get so roaring ' , stinkin ' , no-good drunk ...
I won 't be able to see .
Hey , why don 't you come with us ? It 'll do you some good .
Oh , I don 't think Martha would figure it that way .
Do you have to tell your old woman everything ? Tell her your uncle died .
Tell her you 're going away so you can love her more when you get back .
Good night .
Boy , I 'm so tired of lookin at the guts of secondhand cars ...
I could spit grease .
You know , Marty , if I didn 't get away once in a while , I 'd blow a gasket .
When I come in on Monday ,
if Mr. Johnson looks at me funny just once ...
just once ... you know what I 'm gonna do to him , Marty ?
Hey , Marty !
Look , you keep telling me about a monster .
- All I want to do is clear this thing up . - All right , I agree .
- But I still don 't see why you had to call our folks . - Dave , it 's for you .
- What else could I do ? - Well , give us a chance to find out what happened .
You know we didn 't tear up Doc 's house . How long have you known me ?
All right , I believe you ! But I still don 't think you 're telling me all you know .
- Oh , Dave . - Hello ? Yeah .
Well , young lady , do you mind telling me where you 've been spending the evening ?
- Daddy , it 's all right . - Oh , yes , everything 's fine .
I always stop by the police station to pick up my daughter .
Don 't you realize what this could do to me ?
By morning , it will be all over town .
We were just trying to warn people .
After all , I am principal of the high school .
Young man , this is the last time you 're ever going to take my daughter out !
Steve didn 't do anything wrong !
Mr. Andrews , can you make anything out of all this ? I can 't .
Take it easy , Mr. Martin . We 'll straighten everything out . Hello , son .
- Dad , I saw something terrible tonight . - And nobody 'll believe us .
Mr. Martin , Mr. Andrews ,
uh , apparently Doc Hallen 's office was broken into by vandals tonight .
And Steve and Jane seem to know something about it .
Vandals ? My daughter ?
Well , you don 't think our kids were mixed up in it , do you ?
All we know is that they told us something had happened over at Dr. Hallen 's house .
We 're not accusing anyone of what we found .
We can 't be more definite until we contact Dr. Hallen in Johnsonville .
Dad , it isn 't vandalism ! Dr. Hallen is dead ,
and he was killed by some sort of a monster .
Now , I know because I saw it , Dad .
Lieutenant , I want you to know that Steve is not in the habit of telling lies .
If he says he 's not mixed up in this vandalism , you can be sure it 's the truth .
Did you see this thing too , Jane ?
Well ...
no , not exactly .
Well , look , folks , we 'll all know more in the morning after we 've called Johnsonville .
I think the best thing now is for all of us to go home and get some sleep .
Maybe it 's a good idea , son . We can talk about this some more at home .
Sure , Pop .
Get out of the house as fast as you can . I 'll be over .
Maybe Bertie 's right .
Maybe this is just a gag like those school fraternities were throwing last year .
Remember how they stitched that bathing suit to the statue of General Hayes ?
I don 't think this is a gag .
Why didn 't you book the kids then ?
Why make a big thing of it tonight if we can clear the whole thing up tomorrow ?
Boy , if it was Bertie , he 'd have them strung up by the thumbs by now .
Maybe he would .
Police department .
Hold on . It 's Bertie .
- Hello ? - Dave ?
Yep .
A couple of people thought they heard shots , but weren 't sure .
- Okay , Jim . Doc 's place locked up ? - Yeah .
- Check back in , then . - Right .
We 'll get the truth out of those kids if it takes all night .
- I sent the kids home . - Home ? Are you crazy ?
Jim , we 'll take care of this whole thing tomorrow .
Yes , sir . Is that all ?
Yes , that 's all .
Bertie got some idea what this is ?
I don 't care what Bertie 's ideas are !
He acts like we 're still fighting the war .
Just because some kid smacks into his wife on the turnpike ...
doesn 't make it a crime to be 17 years old !
Okay , so I don 't know what the kids are up to tonight .
But I 'm not gonna throw them into a cell like a couple of vagrants .
We 'll put this puzzle together in the morning .
In the meantime , at least we know where the kids are .
- Hey , where are you going ? - Oh , shhh , Danny .
- Shhh . - Where are you going ?
I 've got something very important to do , Danny , but it 's got to be a secret .
I won 't tell anybody . I 'll go with you .
No , honey , I have to go by myself .
- Will you be back pretty soon ? - Well , I don 't know .
Aren 't you afraid to go out by yourself ?
Yes , I guess I am , Danny .
I 'm not afraid . I 'll guard you .
Oh , no , Danny . You 've got a bigger job to do .
You 've got to stay here and guard Mommy and Daddy .
Oh , they don 't need guarding .
Oh , look , Danny , go on to beddie .
Look , if you go to bed , I might bring you a little dog all your very own .
A dog ! Honest ?
Honest . I cross my heart .
- Oh , boy ! - Now go on up to bed .
- What 's his name ? - Oh , any name you want , Danny .
Can I name him William ?
Oh , that 's a fine name , Danny . Now you better run on up to bed .
- Go on . - Oh , I don 't like William .
You run on to bed , honey .
Steve ? Steve ?
- Was he asleep ? - Yeah .
Do you think he did something wrong ?
I don 't know . I don 't think so .
The police don 't either , or they wouldn 't have sent him home .
I felt that he was keeping something from us .
He did seem more willing to talk when we were at the police station .
Well , I think tomorrow he might talk and we 'll be able to straighten this out .
Maybe , after a good night 's sleep .
Yeah . Good night .
'Night , dear .
You scared me to death . What are you doing here ?
Listen , Jane , I told you to wait over there .
The folks went to bed , so I thought I should just come on over .
All right , come on . Let 's go around the corner .
- Steve ? - Huh ?
Oh , I 'm sorry .
At least I could 've thanked you for coming out tonight .
You didn 't need to .
I never needed to talk to anyone before , not as much as I do now .
Well , we 're in this together , aren 't we , Steve ?
You know , I wish that we ...
I must be getting confused .
I know we saw the old man , I know we took him to the doc 's ...
and I know the doc sent us out to see if we could find out what happened .
So ?
And I know the old man had something on his hand ,
something he couldn 't get off , something that kept getting larger .
I saw that .
And then I ... I think I saw the doc .
He was standing by the window , and he ...
he was trying to get out ...
and that thing was all over him ...
and then ... just dissolved while I stood there .
I think I saw this .
I believe you did .
You know , plenty of people in their right mind thought they saw things that didn 't exist ,
you know , like flying saucers .
The light was just right , and the angle and the imagination .
Boy , if that 's what it is , then this is just an ordinary night .
You and I are gonna go to sleep , and tomorrow when we get up ...
that sun 's gonna shine , just like yesterday .
Good old yesterday .
Steve , well , you believe you did see it , don 't you ?
I don 't know . I-I ...
That 's not true , Steve .
Well , maybe , maybe now you don 't want to believe it .
Maybe you 'd like to tell yourself it didn 't happen .
But , Steve , you 're not the kind of person who can turn your back ...
on something you know is true .
I don 't know .
Well , you actually did see what happened to Dr. Hallen .
How do you know I did ?
Because I know you .
Okay . Now what do we do ?
How do you get people to protect themselves from something they don 't believe in ?
Well , you keep trying and hoping you can find ...
some sort of proof that 'll convince them .
Okay .
I don 't like it much ,
but I guess the only way you can find that is to go out and look for it .
I 'll go get the car .
- You sure you want to go with me ? - Yes .
I wouldn 't give much for our chances ...
wandering around in the middle of the night trying to find something ...
that if we found it , it might kill us .
If we could only find a couple of people to help us .
Hmm . Who ?
Well , your friends , Tony , Mooch and Al .
Hey , you know , that ... that 's worth a try .
Yes , I am here ,
the demon who possesses your soul .
Wait a bit . I am coming for you .
I have so much to show you .
Tony , listen , I wanna see you outside .
Hey , what gives ? I thought you cats didn 't dig spooky shows .
This is important . Outside .
- Hey , what 's up ? - Shhh .
I 'll explain outside . This is important .
You missed most of the picture . You 're not gonna get your money 's worth .
None of us are , unless somebody keeps quiet .
You 're gotta come with us . There 's nobody else we can go to .
- Okay , you kids , knock it off . - Come on !
What ? Walk out of the movie ?
Let 's cut out . You cats gonna make it ?
Not me . I 'm part of this chair , and I can 't move .
Tsk .
Hold up , Mooch !
Hey , all right , Steve , you made us waste our 80 cents . Now , what gives ?
Yeah , what 's the scoop ?
What 's the big idea , Steve ?
Would you believe me if I told you there was something inside of that rock we found ,
something that could wipe out this whole town ?
Knock it off ! Go ahead , Steve .
I saw this thing kill Dr. Hallen tonight .
Kill Dr. Hallen ?
- That 's right . - Well , what is it ?
I don 't know . But one thing 's for sure ,
if it can kill Dr. Hallen , it can kill somebody else .
What do you want us to do , Steve ?
All right , we 're gonna find this thing , and we 're gonna make people believe us .
Let 's try Johnsonville again , Ritchie .
- Okay . - I just saw a strange one .
What do you mean ?
On my way back here , I ran into Mr. Connors coming outta that bar ...
in the building he owns over on Second Street .
He 'd just stopped in , and there was nobody there .
Queerest thing I 've ever seen .
TV was playin ' away . The cash register was there with the money still in it .
Nobody around . No bartender , nobody .
I 'll look in there on the way home .
Forget it . The place is all locked up now .
Why don 't you go home and get some shut-eye ?
You can 't run our shift and yours too , you know ?
Yeah , I know . I wish I knew where those two doctors were , though .
- Any luck , Ritchie ? - Nope , they 're not there .
Want me to call the other hotels ?
There 's a lot of them between here and Johnsonville .
No . I guess you 're right . I guess there 's nothing here that won 't wait till morning .
Well , I 'll see you guys .
- Good night . - Good night .
Well , hello , kids ! Come on in !
You 're just in time for the fun .
- We came to warn you . - Huh ? How ?
- We came here just to warn you ... - Oh , a warning !
Well , that 's fine . I didn 't know you cared .
Hey , folks !
I want you to meet Paul Revere ,
and this is Mrs. Revere .
They 've come to give us a warning about something important .
The British are coming !
Excuse me .
We were just ... just looking for a monster .
Monsters ? You must 've been talking to that guy from Second Street .
Man , I don 't know what they 're serving over there , but it sure must be great stuff .
Listen , we 're trying to tell you . We don 't wanna get served .
Look , I have monsters in here all the time , so beat it .
We don 't serve kids anyway .
Where is he ?
Over there , in the doorway of your dad 's store .
- Come on . Come on . - Come on . Hey !
That 's funny . The door 's not locked .
Do you think it 's been open all night ?
Well , I don 't know . This is Friday .
The store closes at 10 : 00 , and then old Mr. Weinermeyer sweeps up ...
and then he collects all the push carts .
Huh . He works around for a couple of hours before he locks up ,
but I 'm sure he 'd never be this late , not ...
Hey , Mr. Weinermeyer ?
Hey , Mr. Weinermeyer , where are you ?
I 'm gonna turn on the light .
Steve , what is it ?
I don 't know . Oh .
It 's a broom and stuff that Mr. Weinermeyer cleans up with .
It 's spread all over the aisle .
What 's the matter ? Jane !
Here . You all right ?
Yes .
Steve !
Oh , Steve , our parents !
They think we 're home in bed asleep , sound and safe .
Steve , it 's the little dog !
Now listen ! Everything 's gonna be all right . Do you hear me ? Now ...
It 's gonna be all right .
I don 't know if we can stop that thing .
- The dog , Steve . - Take it easy , Jane .
- Oh , Steve , the little dog ! - Don 't cry , Jane .
There 's nothing we can do about it .
Now , Jane , just put this on . It 'll be all right .
Oh , Steve , what are we gonna do ?
I don 't know . That thing probably isn 't far away .
We 've gotta get out of here before it comes back for us .
Now , come on . All right ?
There they are !
- Hey , where you kids been ? - Hey , it 's in there !
- You 're kidding ! - I wish I were kidding . It 's in there .
- He got the little dog . - Oh , you mean the old man 's dog .
- We just seen him running down the street . - Oh , Steve !
- What do we do now ? - We 're gonna call the police . They want evidence .
There 's a phone at the corner !
- Hmm . - Go on !
- You talk to him , Tony . - Me ? Why me ?
I 'm supposed to be home asleep . If they think I 'm loose , they 'll never believe us .
Yeah , here 's a dime . Come on . Come on .
- Hey , what 'll I say ? - Ask for Dave .
And you give it to him straight . You tell him to get out to the store quick .
Tell him to bring every piece of hardware he can find in the police station .
Hello . Police department .
Is ... Who 's this ?
Arthur who ?
Is every kid in town in on this ?
I don 't know who this is , but you 're going to wish you 'd never thought of this .
Hello ? Hello ?
Big deal ! I 'd like to take that dime ...
- Bert ? - Yeah .
Wouldn 't you know it ?
All right , we tried to do it the right way , now we 're gonna wake this town up ourselves .
- Yeah , yeah , but how ? - Yeah , how ?
Any way we can think of .
We 've got to stop being a baby-sitting service and start being a police department .
- Just kids , Jim . - Just kids ?
That 's about he craziest argument I 've ever heard .
Every criminal in the world was a kid once . What does it prove ?
You know what I think ? I think they 've got it in for me .
- You ? - Yeah .
They 've heard about my war record , and it bugs them .
They 're trying to break me down , see what makes me tick .
Anything they can try , they try .
Aw , I don 't think so , Jim .
- What the ... - Sounds like New Year 's Eve .
Hello ?
I don 't know either ... Lady ?
Police department .
Looks like everybody in town 's getting up .
What 's going on here ? Why , that 's an air raid !
Pull yourself together .
Oh , it 's probably only ... No , maybe it 's the real thing .
It isn 't a drill . Where is my civil defense helmet ?
Where is it ? Here we are .
Here we go .
- Fire . - Fire ?
This has never happened before . What am I gonna wear ?
Henry , Danny 's gone !
What ?
And Jane too !
- Calm down , Elizabeth . - I looked in their rooms . They 're both gone !
- Are you sure ? - Yes ! Yes !
Well , maybe they 're down here .
Here 's Danny .
Danny !
What are you doing here ?
I 'm guarding you .
Guarding us ?
Guarding us against what , darling ?
I don 't know .
Has everyone in this fool town gone crazy ?
Danny , do you know where Janey is ?
She 's just gone .
I 'm going to get to the bottom of this right now .
Come , Elizabeth .
Hey , what 's going on here ?
What 's the matter ?
All right now , kill the ho ... Kill the horns !
All right , knock off the noise now !
Listen to ... Listen to me ! Now listen to me , everybody !
This town is in danger . Several people have been killed already .
Now we had to make this noise so you 'd listen to us , so we could warn you .
If we 're in trouble , where are the police ?
You ! Boy , this time you 've really hung yourself .
Now look ... Now look , sarge , just give me a chance to talk to them , that 's all .
I don 't know what kind of a game it is you 're playing ,
but whatever it is it 's gonna stop right now !
Here comes Dave .
What 's going on here , Jim ? Steve !
Dave , make ' em listen to me ! There is a monster !
We saw it again in Dad 's store . Dave , it 's bigger now .
Your story 's gotten bigger now , kid .
Dave , look at me ! Do I look like somebody who 's playing a practical joke ?
Am I laughing ... or am I scared stiff ?
- What are you gonna do ? - He 's telling the truth .
Oh , wait a minute ! It 's one thing to make a fool out of yourself ,
but it 's another thing to make a fool out of the police department and the town .
- He 's right , Lieutenant . - You 've been wrong before .
Maybe I have ! But as long as I 'm in charge of this town 's police force ,
I 'm gonna handle this thing the way I see fit .
And your job right now is to help me restore some order around here .
Yes , sir .
Okay , everybody , quiet down a minute .
Quiet down , please !
Listen , this is an emergency ,
and it can affect every one of us .
That 's all I can tell you right now .
But we 're trying to get things under control .
In order to do that , we have to clear this area immediately .
So please go home and stay there .
We 'll keep in touch with you through your radio station .
Now , be careful pulling your cars out of this area .
Go home slowly and quietly .
Just keep calm . Everything 's gonna be all right .
- Anything I can do to help ? - Lieutenant , what 's going on ?
Ask your daughter , Mr. Martin . She can tell you more than I can .
Phil , can your boys give us a hand clearing this area ?
Sure .
- Do you have any guns ? - A couple of ' em .
- Get ' em . - Say , Dave , what is this thing ?
I don 't know . But if it 's in the market , we 'll all know in a few minutes .
Now all the images of horror ,
the demons of your mind crowd in on you to destroy you .
Phil , can you move your truck over to the door ...
and shine your big light into the market ?
- Sure , Dave . - All right .
What the ...
Hey , who 's in the store ?
Huh ?
There 's nobody in here but us monsters .
Dave , it 's at the theater !
Don 't go in , Jim . This won 't do any good .
It 's the most horrible thing I 've ever seen in my life .
- So what is it ? - Come on , we 've gotta clear this area .
All right , step back !
Everybody step back !
Here it comes !
Danny !
No , Danny , wait !
What goes ? What happened out there ?
Oh , I almost got it .
No , Danny ! Danny , we can 't stay here . Come with me , Danny .
Listen , it 's too late . Let 's see if we can get out the back .
Wait a minute ! What 's this ?
- What happened ? - It 's all over us .
- What do you mean ? What 's the matter ? - Take it easy !
Jim , get the telephone company . Have them connect you with the diner , fast .
I 'm not gonna stay here !
Now , wait a minute ! You open that door , and we 've had it !
- You wanna die ? - What are we supposed to do ?
- Hello ? Yeah . - Steve ?
- That thing is all over us ! - Watch out !
I don 't think it can be killed .
- We 've gotta try one more thing . - Okay .
- Is everybody all right ? - Okay , but not for long .
We can drop a power line on it . Do you understand ?
There should be enough juice in that line to burn the thing to a crisp .
Yeah , get everyone down in the cellar .
We 'll do it in 60 seconds , Steve .
Cellar !
Okay .
Jim , here 's a rifle .
- Take the phone , Ritchie . - All right .
Dave , this baby should do the trick . It 's all set to go .
Try not to miss , Jim .
Okay , let 's have those lights !
Fifteen seconds .
It 's quiet now . I think the upstairs is clear .
Good . Keep your ear to that phone , Ritchie .
Okay , Jim .
It didn 't work .
Why don 't you do something ? Do something !
Elizabeth .
The diner 's on fire .
Can 't we put it out ?
Any suggestions how ?
Anyway , not enough oxygen in there to keep a fire going for ten minutes .
There 's something burning .
- Listen , is there any other way out of here ? - The windows .
Hey , now you be quiet . Shhh .
- I 'm not afraid . - Well , I know you 're not .
Hey , listen , Jane ...
It 'll be all right .
Honey , lay your head down and try to go to sleep .
Everything will be all right , Danny .
Hey , there 's the fire ! I 'll stop it !
Wait a minute . Let me have that a minute .
CO2 ! Hey , that 's it ! It 's cold !
That 's why it didn 't come in the ice box after us . It can 't stand cold .
- You got any more of these things ? Huh ? - No .
This thing 's running out . The phone . Hey , Dave !
Hey , Dave ! Hey , Da ... Anybody on the phone ?
Hey , Dave ! Dave , can you hear me ?
CO2 !
Dave !
- What did he say ? - Al , what 's up ?
Shhh . Quiet .
CO2 ?
Phil ! Phil , do you got any CO2 extinguishers ?
Not many . Some soda acid .
Well , get the CO2s out here and start hitting around those cellar windows .
- What ? - Just do it , Phil !
And check these buildings for fire extinguishers . But only the CO2 kind .
- Bring back every one you can get your hands on . - All right . Okay .
Hey , maybe we can help . Let 's get some guys together .
- Lieutenant , I know where there are 20 extinguishers - Good . Where ?
- At the high school . Who can go with me ? - Hey , right here , Mr. Martin .
Well , what are we waiting for ? Let 's go .
Okay , let 's go . Over here , Mr. Martin .
This thing 's running out !
Hey , Dave ! Dave ?
Dave , CO2 fire extinguishers !
Dave , can you hear me ? CO2 !
Okay , come on .
- Oh , it 's locked . - Of course it 's locked .
- Here comes Mr. Martin . - Here comes the principal .
We could only find four or five of these things , Dave .
- How many of them do you need ? - A lot more than that .
- Keep looking . It 's all we can do . - Okay .
Dave , Colonel Spaulding got me through to Washington .
They thought I was crazy at first , but they 're getting someone now .
Hey , here come the kids !
Our power 's still out , so we can 't do much in the way of refrigeration .
We think we 've got it under control , but we won 't rest easy until it 's frozen solid .
Now ...
No , it 's too big for that , and it 's impossible to cut it .
No , sir , a bomb would spread it all over the country .
Look , this thing has killed probably 40 or 50 people since last night .
In a few hours , we 're gonna have the sun overhead .
I think you should send us the biggest transport plane you have ...
and take this thing up to the Arctic or somewhere where it 'll never thaw out .
Oh , Daddy ! Oh , Daddy !
Let me see you , son . Let me see my boy .
- Nice work , Steve . You okay ? - Yeah , I 'm okay .
Dave , listen , I wanna ...
Well , I wanna thank you for getting us out of there .
You know , for a while , I didn 't think we were gonna make it .
- That makes two of us . - What are they gonna do with that thing , Dave ?
Well , the Air Force is sending a Globemaster in . They 're flying it to the Arctic .
It 's not dead , is it ?
No , it 's not .
- Just frozen . - I don 't think it can be killed .
But at least we 've got it stopped .
Yeah , as long as the Arctic stays cold .